

Angélica

HERRERA ALBA

WEB DEV I WEB DESIGN I PYTHON DEV I GIT I
DATA VISUALIZATION I WEB SCRAPPING I BI I
EXCEL

- Bogotá, Colombia
- angelicaherreraalba@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/angelicaherreraalba

PROFESIONAL PROFILE

Enthusiastic python and web developer with high attention to detail, physicist from Universidad de Los Andes, with great affinity for programming in different languages and for the UI and UX. Extensive experience in data analysis and data modeling in Python, and performing as a teacher assistant in Physics and Systems Engineering courses. Advanced Python with libraries such as: Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Beautiful Soup, Django, among others.

EDUCATION

2017 - 2022

Physics I Universidad de Los Andes

RELEVANT COURSES

- Computational Tools.
- Computational Methods.
- Algorithmic and Object Oriented Programming I y II.
- Business Challenge: Computer Vision

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DANE I Data Analyst and Web Developer

September 2022 - December 2022

I worked doing data analysis related with the DANE recruitment process, automating processes, cleaning data and presenting results. In addition, I worked for 1 month as a Web Developer, planning and building the Login/Sign Up form of the new mobile app of DANE.

Universidad de los Andes I Data Scientist

Agosto 2021 - Octubre 2021

Experience solving two requirements for the companies Rappi and Whale & Jaguar. Artificial intelligence models were investigated, studied and implemented, and all the analysis and results presentation to the companies was performed. It was possible to provide high quality solutions and learn to investigate in this area.

Universidad de Los Andes I Teacher Assistant

2020 - 2022

Design and grade exams alongside the professor, guidance and clarification of concepts and doubts of the students in the Clinic of Problems, Cupitaller and in various subjects in which I had an outstanding performance that allowed me to access this position.

COMPUTER SKILLS

- Operating Systems: Linux, Microsoft Windows.
- Languages: Python, C++, Java, HTML, CSS.
- Software: Power BI, Git, Latex, Office.

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native, C2)

English (C1, EF Institut)

French (B1, Alliance Française)

German (A1, Sprach Institut)

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Universidad de Los Andes I Undergraduate Thesis

<u>Neutrino - Nucleon cross section calculations at ultrahigh energies.</u>

Calculation of the cross section of neutrino – nucleon at high energies, under the advice of Professor Juan Carlos Sanabria, Ph.D. A simulation was carried out in C++, where, by means of Python, the descriptive analysis of the returned data was performed. During the development of this thesis, the use of computational and statistical tools was necessary in order to carry out a correct analysis with mathematical rigor and visualize data of high interest.

SKILLS



Critical analytical thinking



Creativity in problem solving.



Strategic data visualization



Attention to detail



Fast learner



Easy decision maker